<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Features on Bala Subramanyam Lanka</title>
    <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/categories/features/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Features on Bala Subramanyam Lanka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 13:41:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thisisbalu.github.io/categories/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advantages of SVG (Scalable Vector Graphics)</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/advantages-of-svg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 13:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/advantages-of-svg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SVG is trending technology in the internet world. There are many advantages of SVG. In crisp, SVG which stands for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.balasubramanyamlanka.com/infinitely-scalable-svg-scalable-vector-graphics/&#34;&gt;Scalable Vector Graphics&lt;/a&gt; is used to define vector-based graphics for the Web. It was introduced by W3C in the year 1999 and it became W3C Recommendation from the year 2001&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infinitely Scalable SVG – Scalable Vector Graphics</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/infinitely-scalable-svg-scalable-vector-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 18:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/infinitely-scalable-svg-scalable-vector-graphics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scalable Vector Graphics, widely known as SVG is becoming popular now a days. Scalable Vector Graphics is an open standard that was developed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Wide_Web_Consortium&#34;&gt;World Wide Web Consortium(W3C)&lt;/a&gt; in 1999. SVG is an XML based vector image format for 2D Graphics that has support for interactivity and animation. In the year 2003 it became W3c recommendation. It is text based, which means you can create SVG in simple text file. Simply it is an image that will be written in xml with some of the predefined xml attributes and tags.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Glyph Icon Libraries available in Market</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/best-glyph-icon-libraries-available-in-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 18:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/best-glyph-icon-libraries-available-in-market/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are not using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.balasubramanyamlanka.com/what-are-glyph-icons/&#34;&gt;Glyph Icon&lt;/a&gt; Libraries in you designing, then you are missing a lot! Yes glyph icons libraries are very useful, very flexible and very easy to implement via markup in our web pages. There are many glyph icon libraries out there in the internet. Here i have collected the good glyph icon libraries that are updated frequently with the newer stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are Glyph Icons?</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/what-are-glyph-icons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 18:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/what-are-glyph-icons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Glyph is a Greek word which had different meanings with respective to the different perspectives. For an example in typography glyph is a elemental symbol that can represented in the different styles that represents the same elemental symbol, in Architecture glyph is an ornamental carved groove, _in Computing glyph is a small graphic symbol. _There comes our perspective! Yes computing – Glyph Icons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wrapper Classes in Java</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/wrapper-classes-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 04:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/wrapper-classes-in-java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Java is an Object Oriented Language which views everything as an object. For an instance a simple file can be treated as an object , an address of a system can be seen as an object , an image can be treated as an object (with java.awt.Image) and a simple data type can be converted into an object (with wrapper classes).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write Once Run Anywhere WORA</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/write-once-run-anywhere-wora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 04:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/write-once-run-anywhere-wora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is Write Once Run Anywhere WORA? In simple we can term it as Cross Platform Compatibility. It is some times Expressed as WORE – Write Once Run Everywhere. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Features of Java</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/features-of-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 04:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/features-of-java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are 12 features of Java. Sometimes features of Java are also called as Java Buzzwords. Features are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Redefined the term Internet</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/java-redefined-the-term-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 04:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/java-redefined-the-term-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today lets see how java changed the Internet. The Internet helped catapult Java to the forefront of programming, and Java, in turn, had a profound effect on the Internet. In addition to simplifying web programming in general, Java innovated a new type of networked program called the applet that changed the way the online world thought about content. The main factors that changed the internet are discussed below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Team</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/java-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/java-team/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes this post is about the people who created Java Language. After thorough search over internet and referring many books i got all the names of the people who made Java a Popular programming language.  James Gosling is the one who lead the team. Following members are the Java Team.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Java got started?</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/how-java-got-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 14:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/how-java-got-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;offscreen&#34; id=&#34;how-java-got-started&#34;&gt;How Java got started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java was conceived by &lt;strong&gt;James Gosling&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Patrick Naughton&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Chris Warth&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Ed Frank&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Mike Sheridan&lt;/strong&gt; at Sun Microsystems, Inc. in 1991. It took 18 months to develop the first working version. This language was initially called “Oak,” but was renamed “Java” in 1995. Between the initial implementation of Oak in the fall of 1992 and the public announcement of Java in the spring of 1995, many more people contributed to the design and evolution of the language. &lt;strong&gt;Bill Joy&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Arthur van Hoff&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Jonathan Payne&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Frank Yellin&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Tim Lindholm&lt;/strong&gt; were key contributors to the maturing of the original prototype.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Java Mascot – Duke</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/the-java-mascot-duke/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 18:40:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/the-java-mascot-duke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before knowing about the Duke, The Java Mascot let us know about mascot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a Mascot?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mascot is any person, animal, or object thought to bring luck or anything used to represent a group with a common public identity, such as a school, professional sports team, society, military unit, or brand name. Mascots are also used as fictional, representative spokespeople for consumer products.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Versions and Features</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/java-versions-and-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 19:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/java-versions-and-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Java is the language that is updated with new versions and features frequently. J2SE 8 is the present version of the Java. Lets drive into the history of the Java Versions and Features in detail. All the versions of the Java have their Code Names (&lt;a href=&#34;http://javaindetail.com/2014/08/26/java-code-names/&#34; title=&#34;Java Code Names&#34;&gt;Click here for code names and release dates&lt;/a&gt;) Following are the Versions and Features of Java.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Code Names</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/java-code-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 19:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/java-code-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We daily program, daily use Java, daily think about Java but many of us do not know code names of Java versions. Yes code names for each version released till date. Let us know in detail about the Java code names in Java In Detail :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
