<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>big data on Bala Subramanyam Lanka</title>
    <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/tags/big-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in big data on Bala Subramanyam Lanka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 15:36:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thisisbalu.github.io/tags/big-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unstructured Data</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/unstructured-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 15:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/unstructured-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unstructured data is the data that does not follow a specific format. We can also define unstructured data as the information that does not have a pre defined data model or not in a organised manner. If 20 percent of the data available to enterprises is structured data, the other 80 percent is unstructured. If there is a chance to analyse this whole data, we can see this world from the different perspective!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Storage and Analysis Problems Faced in Digital Universe</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/data-storage-and-analysis-problems-faced-in-digital-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 17:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/data-storage-and-analysis-problems-faced-in-digital-universe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data Storage and Analysis of the stored data is currently the problem in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.balasubramanyamlanka.com/data-how-it-is-important-in-this-digital-universe/&#34;&gt;Digital Universe&lt;/a&gt;. When I am studying 7th standard, that is in 2003 there used to be Floppy Disks in use! Yes those disks have storage capacity of 1.44 MB and with access speed of 60kbps. Now a days we have flash storage upto 128 GB with access speed of 60mbps to 120 mbps. We can just imagine how fast the storage capabilities and access speeds have been increased.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data! How it is important in this Digital Universe</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/data-how-it-is-important-in-this-digital-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 17:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/data-how-it-is-important-in-this-digital-universe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We live in the Date Age. It is very hard to measure the total volume of the data that is stored electronically in the universe. The estimated size of the data of Digital Universe in 2006 is 0.18 zettabytes, in 2011 it increased to 1.8 zettabytes, in 2013 it increased &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emc.com/leadership/digital-universe/2014iview/executive-summary.htm&#34;&gt;more to 4.4 zettabytes&lt;/a&gt;! According to the new estimates this Digital Universe is going to increase by 10 factor in 2020. By 2020 it will be increased to 44 zettabytes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
