<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rule Solutions for Office on Bala Subramanyam Lanka</title>
    <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/tags/rule-solutions-for-office/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rule Solutions for Office on Bala Subramanyam Lanka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 20:25:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thisisbalu.github.io/tags/rule-solutions-for-office/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Synchronizing Rules and RuleDocs – Rule Solutions for Office, ODM</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/synchronising-rules-ruledocs-rule-solutions-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 20:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/synchronising-rules-ruledocs-rule-solutions-office/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;shortdesc&#34;&gt;
  RuleDocs are Microsoft Office documents that contain your rules, decision tables, and ruleflows. Rules and ruleflows are stored in Word documents, while decision tables are stored as spreadsheets in Excel. We use t to edit and manage rules offline. You can also use them to present the rules together with documentation and supporting information, including the original policy or requirement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule Solutions for Office Installation – IBM ODM</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/rule-solutions-office-installation-odm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 17:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/rule-solutions-office-installation-odm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;keyword&#34;&gt;Rule Solutions for Office&lt;/span&gt; enables you to edit business rules in Microsoft Office documents called RuleDocs. You can update and share rules with RuleDocs, which can also provide supporting documentation and information such as the original policies for the rules. &lt;span class=&#34;keyword&#34;&gt;Rule Solutions &lt;/span&gt;works in conjunction with &lt;span class=&#34;keyword&#34;&gt;Decision Center&lt;/span&gt;, which serves as a workspace for business users to collaborate on authoring, editing, organizing, and searching for business rules.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
