<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wordpress on Bala Subramanyam Lanka</title>
    <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/categories/wordpress/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wordpress on Bala Subramanyam Lanka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 15:39:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thisisbalu.github.io/categories/wordpress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why WordPress restricts uploading SVG files?</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/why-wordpress-restricts-uploading-svg-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 15:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/why-wordpress-restricts-uploading-svg-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress media uploader restricts uploading SVG files into WordPress. It throws an error message “Sorry, this file type is not permitted for security reasons.” Yes! for security reasons WordPress blocks uploading SVG files. Error Dialog will be as follows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading SVG files through WordPress Media Uploader</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/uploading-svg-files-through-wordpress-media-uploader/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 17:03:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/uploading-svg-files-through-wordpress-media-uploader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Uploading SVG files through media uploader in WordPress is an issue faced by all the WordPress users or the bloggers who are interested in adding SVG image files in to their posts. SVG (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.balasubramanyamlanka.com/infinitely-scalable-svg-scalable-vector-graphics/&#34;&gt;Scalable Vector Graphics&lt;/a&gt;) files are very popular because of their infinite scalability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inline SVG in WordPress Post</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/inline-svg-in-wordpress-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 17:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/inline-svg-in-wordpress-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.balasubramanyamlanka.com/infinitely-scalable-svg-scalable-vector-graphics/&#34;&gt;Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG)&lt;/a&gt; is a trending technology. As SVG is infinitely scalable graphics, it is widely used. There is a problem in using these graphics inside the a WordPress post. Yes, there are two problems with SVG in WordPress post. First thing is that you cannot upload a SVG image into the WordPress uploads and the second one is we cannot use inline SVG in WordPress post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Excerpt Length in WordPress</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/custom-excerpt-length-in-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 15:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/custom-excerpt-length-in-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In WordPress, excerpt means a _short extract from the blog post. _The default length of the excerpt in WordPress is 55 characters. For the customisation purposes setting user defined length to the excerpt in WordPress is needed at times. This needs adding a small php function in to functions.php file. As mentioned above default length of the excerpt is 55 characters, to override the  default functionality excerpt length we have to add a filter in the same file.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Excerpt More and Custom Excerpt More Link in WordPress</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/custom-excerpt-more-and-custom-excerpt-more-link-in-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 20:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/custom-excerpt-more-and-custom-excerpt-more-link-in-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before talking about the custom excerpt more in WordPress let’s talk about the general meaning of the excerpt. It means a &lt;em&gt;short extract from anything&lt;/em&gt;. So when it comes to the WordPress, excerpt means _a short extract from the blog post. _Excerpt in the blog is one of the important thing that every WordPress user uses it for the customisation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing Query Strings from Static Resources</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/removing-query-strings-from-static-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 17:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/removing-query-strings-from-static-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are a WordPress user, removing of query strings from static resources does matter in the website’s performance. When I was developing my blog’s theme I faced the same issues. In order to remove the query strings from the static resources we can write a small piece of javascript or write a simple function in php. I would prefer writing the php code in the functions.php file to remove query strings from static resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
