<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hadoop on Bala Subramanyam Lanka</title>
    <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/tags/hadoop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hadoop on Bala Subramanyam Lanka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 17:08:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thisisbalu.github.io/tags/hadoop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Structured Data</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/structured-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 17:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/structured-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many definitions for structured data. The term structured data can be referred as the data that resides in a fixed field within a record or a file. It can be also defined as the data that has a defined length and format. Examples of the structured data include numbers, dates, strings, records in databases, spreadsheets, etc.,. This kind of data can be easily entered, stored, analysed and queried.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History of Hadoop</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/history-of-hadoop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 13:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/history-of-hadoop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;History of Hadoop had started in the year 2002 with the project Apache Nutch. Hadoop was created by Doug Cutting, the creator of Apache Lucene, the widely used text search library. Hadoop has its origins in Apache Nutch, an open source web search engine which itself is a part of Lucene Project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origin of the Name Hadoop</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/origin-of-the-name-hadoop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 17:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/origin-of-the-name-hadoop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Origin of the Name Hadoop is not from an acronym and the name Hadoop doesn’t have any specific meaning too. It’s just a made up name! Hadoop Project’s creator, Doug Cutting, explains how the name came in to existing —&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Storage and Analysis Problems Faced in Digital Universe</title>
      <link>https://thisisbalu.github.io/data-storage-and-analysis-problems-faced-in-digital-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 17:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thisisbalu.github.io/data-storage-and-analysis-problems-faced-in-digital-universe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data Storage and Analysis of the stored data is currently the problem in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.balasubramanyamlanka.com/data-how-it-is-important-in-this-digital-universe/&#34;&gt;Digital Universe&lt;/a&gt;. When I am studying 7th standard, that is in 2003 there used to be Floppy Disks in use! Yes those disks have storage capacity of 1.44 MB and with access speed of 60kbps. Now a days we have flash storage upto 128 GB with access speed of 60mbps to 120 mbps. We can just imagine how fast the storage capabilities and access speeds have been increased.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
